M. RAM KUMAR () Featured

System Analyst(plsql Developer) seeking roles in Software Development,Software Design,Project Management,Database Development,Data Migration,Performance Tuning,Development,Client Engagement,Requirement Gathering,WinScp,Oracle,Putty,JIRA,SQL,SVN,Git



Current Designation: System Analyst Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: ValueLabs Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: System Analyst, Software Developer, Software Development, Software Design, Project Management, Database

Development, Data Migration, Performance Tuning, Application Development, Client Engagement, Requirement

Gathering, WinScp, Oracle, Putty, JIRA, SQL, SVN, Git

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Competent Professional with 8.5 years of experience in building software solutions by studying information needs, conferring with users, studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes

Led the design, development, testing and implementation in Client-Server Application Development using SQL, PL/SQL and SQL*Loader

Expertise in Database Development Activities like Database Creation & Maintenance, Reporting, Performance Monitoring & Tuning, Troubleshooting

and Documentation

Domain expertise in Telecom, Educational, Insurance & Health Care domains

Worked with SQL*Loader to import the date into the temporary tables and then generating reports for the business needs Initiated Materialized View to query separately with the aggregate copy of the tables and managed Query Optimization techniques.

Work Experience

ValueLabs as System Analyst Oct 2018 to Till Date

Key Result Areas:

Formulating solutions for given technical specifications; installing application software and deploying customizations and contributing to code reviews

Taking part in requirement gathering for enhancements and creation of high-level as well as detailed-level design documents

Building automated deployments through the use of technologies; supporting machine learning, forecasting, predicting trends, analyzing cash-flow and developing new products

Working with stakeholders during problem diagnoses, requirements gathering, detailed level design, development, system test and production implementation to ensure that optimal resolutions were achieved

Streamlining the pattern matching operators, joins, set operators, constraints, view with check option, read only and nvl functions

Managing the PL/SQL Database objects like Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Cursors, Packages, Global Temporary Tables

Experience in SQL tuning, Table Partitioning, Oracle Tools and Utilities, Dynamic SQL and Exception Handling techniques

Formulating PL/SQL package, procedures, functions according to the business requirement

Creating schema level triggers and used triggers for auditing purposes

Using latest features to optimize performance (Bulk Bind, Collections)

Conducting code review works before deploying code into QA/UAT environments

Documenting impact analysis, detail designs, test cases, and user guides

- Decode, case, NVL & coalesce functions
- Data migration using PL/SQL stored Procedures
- Building stored procedures using Execute Immediate (Dynamic SQL) and Records

Using inbuilt procedures, packages, exceptions and functions more effectively for the business needs.

Created complex report queries using Sub Queries, Inline View Correlated Sub Queries, Joins and Set Operators.

Timely resolution of Production Support Tickets, including the monitoring, root cause analysis and reporting

Designing detailed technical components utilizing high-level architecture, design patterns & reusable code, considering functional & non-functional requirements; writing complex queries for reports

Employing best practices for coding, architecture, and security; ensuring high quality development of internal & external applications

Managing development & integration of various modules within the framework

Identifying ways to integrate data from the client's other systems to report on multiple sources of information

Performing analytical interpretation of highly specialized technical and analytical information used to compose detailed documentation and reports

Creating business requirements, source to target mappings, data models, and universe designs in order to assist in the development of highly efficient and highly scalable business intelligence solutions

Conducting integration and unit testing; reviewing detailed design, code & test cases; resolved various defects, errors and issues encountered

Enhancing modules delivered to production by rewriting and developing new code to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of systems

Reporting overall status of the project to the client and senior management

Gained automation experience in small utility development to cover manual work/reporting using Java Applet, Java Swing and C#.NET

Wrote database objects and worked with client side teams for integration of biometric authentication solution with core banking solutions

HP as Software Developer Nov 2017 to Sep 2018

Beyontec Solutions as Software Developer May 2016 to Oct 2017

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Anna University in 2009

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, Windows	
SQL Developer, SVN, Jira, Git,	
Putty, WinScp, Rundeck	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Tamil	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time